Ford Foundation records, Building Services, Ford Foundation artwork photographs FA1723
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Artwork photograph files, 1963-1969, 2019; 1; 2.66 Cubic Feet About 7 LTR size Hollinger boxes
  - Scheidel, Franz Anton von - Eskimo in Kayak/Two Eskimo Hunters, 1967; File contains still images. Images consist of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 6, Folder 179)
    Art description: Franz Anton von Scheidel (Austrian, 1731-1801) - Eskimo in Kayak, circa 1775 Watercolor, 10 x 19 1/4" (Sight) - Two Eskimo Hunters, circa 1775 Watercolor, 13 3/4 x 16 1/2" (Sight) Purchased from B. Weinreb, London, United Kingdom
  - Schiele, Egon - Portrait of Arthur Roessler, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of photographs and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 180)
    Art description: Egon Schiele (Austrian, 1890-1918) Portrait of Arthur Roessler Charcoal, 12 x 11 1/2" Purchased from L'Art Ancien, Zurich, Switzerland
  - Schoen, Erhard - "Das Munich und Pfaffen Haid, Niemand zu lieb noch zu laid", 1967; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 181)
    Art description: Erhard Schoen (German, 1491-1542) "Das Munich und Pfaffen Haid, Niemand zu lieb noch zu laid" (To be a monk or a priest, should not be too much liked or too unpleasant for anyone) Woodcut, 15 1/8 x 19 1/2" Purchased from August Laube, Zurich, Switzerland
  - Segonzac, Andre Dunoyer de - Le Pont Neuf, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 182)
    Art description: Andre Dunoyer de Segonzac (French, born 1884) Le Pont Neuf, 1963 Color lithograph. 17 x 13" Purchased from Berggruen, Paris, France
  - Senape, Antonio - Catania with Mt. Etna, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 183)
    Art description: Antonio Senape (Italian, early 19th Century) Catania with Mt. Etna Pen on tracing paper, 9 x 13 1/2" Purchased from Yvonne Ffrench, London, United Kingdom
  - Shiba Kokan - Two-panel screen of antiquarian possessions, including books and vases, 1967; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 184)
    Art description: Attributed to Shiba Kokan (Japanese, 1747-1818) Two-panel screen of antiquarian possessions, including books and vases, circa 1800 Painted in color on silk, 52 x 39 1/2" overall Purchased from Edwin D. Hewitt, Tokyo, Japan
  - Sickert, Walter Richard - The Actor Manager (Mrs. D'Oyley Carte), 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 185)
    Art description: Walter Richard Sickert (English, 1860-1942) The Actor Manager (Mrs. D'Oyley Carte) Etching, 9 x 8 7/8" Purchased from Ernest Brown and Phillips, London, United Kingdom
  - Sickert, Walter Richard - The Mogul Tavern, Drury Lane, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 186)
    Art description: Walter Richard Sickert (English, 1860-1942) The Mogul Tavern, Drury Lane Etching, 7 3/4 x 5 1/2" Purchased from Ernest Brown and Phillips, London, United Kingdom
  - Sickert, Walter Richard - Old Heffel of Rowton's, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 187)
    Art description: Walter Richard Sickert (English, 1860-1942) Old Heffel of Rowton's Engraving, 12 x 10" Purchased from Ernest Brown and Phillips, London, United Kingdom
  - Silvestre, Israel - The Water Organ in the Gardens of the Villa D'este, Tivoli, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 188-190)
    Art description: Israel Silvestre (French, 1621-1691) The Water Organ in the Gardens of the Villa D'este, Tivoli Pen, brown ink and wash, 8 3/4 x 12 13/16" Purchased from Schaeffer Galleries, New York, New York
  - Smirke, Robert - Scenes from Shakespeare, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 6, Folder 191)
    Art description: Robert Smirke (English, 1752-1845) - Petruchio and Katherina - Falstaff in the Tavern - Falstaff in the Linen Basket - The Shrew Tamed - Malvolio and Olivia - Lear Chides Cordelia - Juliet's Nurse - The Winter's Tale Oil on board, 5 3/4 x 4 1/4" Purchased from Thos. Agnew and Sons, London, United Kingdom
  - Spanish, Anonymous, 15th-16th Century - Illuminated manuscript page, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 192)
    Art description: Spanish, Anonymous, 15th-16th Century Illuminated manuscript page Parchment, 30 3/4 x 23" Purchased from August Laube, Zurich, Switzerland
  - Spanish, Anonymous, 16th Century - Illuminated manuscript page, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 193)
    Art description: Spanish, Anonymous, 16th Century Illuminated manuscript page: Initial "D" containing the figure of King David kneeling in prayer Antiphonal on vellum, 31 1/2 x 21 1/4" (Sight) Purchased from David Magee, San Francisco, California The photograph that corresponds to the negative in the file can be found in Miscellaneous artwork, 1967-1968, Box 7, Folder 224-225
  - Springer, Cornelis - View in Dordrecht, the Vischstraat, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 194)
    Art description: Cornelis Springer (Dutch, 1817-1891) View in Dordrecht, the Vischstraat, 1882 Black and red chalk and wash, 23 1/2 x 19" Purchased from Bernard Houthakker, Amsterdam, Netherlands
  - Steinberg, Saul - The Orator, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 195)
    Art description: Saul Steinberg (American, born 1914) The Orator, 1961 Pen and ink, 23 1/2 x 14 3/8" Purchased from Berggruen, Paris, France
  - Steinlen, Alexandre Theophile - The Candidate, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 196)
    Art description: Alexandre Theophile Steinlen (French, 1859-1923) The Candidate Black crayon, 14 x 11" Purchased from Charles E. Slatkin, Inc. Galleries, New York, New York
  - Steinlen, Alexandre Theophile - Mother and Child, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 197)
    Art description: Alexandre Theophile Steinlen (French, 1859-1923) Mother and Child Charcoal, 15 x 12 1/4" Purchased from Ernest Brown and Phillips, London, United Kingdom
  - Stern, Giovanni - Bernini's Obelisk in the Piazza Navona, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 198)
    Art description: Giovanni Stern (Italian, 1734-1794) Bernini's Obelisk in the Piazza Navona, 1767 (or 1761) Watercolor, 25 5/8 x 16 1/2" Purchased from B. Weinreb, London, United Kingdom
  - Sutherland, Graham - Gorse on Hills with Stricken Sun, 1966-1968; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 199)
    Art description: Graham Sutherland (English, born 1903) Gorse on Hills with Stricken Sun, 1941 Purchased from Thos. Agnew and Sons, London, United Kingdom
  - Tchelitchew, Pavel - Project for the costume of the Queen of the Night in Mozart's "Magic Flute", 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 200)
    Art description: Pavel Tchelitchew, (Russian, 1898-1957) Project for the costume of the Queen of the Night in Mozart's "Magic Flute", 1942 Sepia and India ink, 11 1/2 x 16 5/8" (Sight) Purchased from Durlacher Bros., New York, New York
  - Tiepolo, Giovanni Domencio - Fame with Angels and Cherubs in the Clouds, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 201)
    Art description: Giovanni Domencio Tiepolo (Italian, 1727-1804) Fame with Angels and Cherubs in the Clouds Pen and brown ink, brown wash, 8 x 11 1/8" (Sight) Purchased from Charles E. Slatkin, Inc. Galleries, New York, New York
  - Troost, William - Classical Ruins, 1966; File contains still images. Images are photograph negatives. There are also images on photo stock paper. (Box 6, Folder 202)
    Art description: William Troost (Dutch, 1684-1759) Classical Ruins Gouache, 7 7/8 x 5 3/4" (Sight) Purchased from Mathias Komor, New York, New York
  - Vallotton, Felix - Pont a Dax, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 203)
    Art description: Felix Vallotton (French, 1865-1925) Pont a Dax, 1917 Pencil, 10 x 7 3/4" Purchased from Mrs. Walter Feilchenfeldt, Zurich, Switzerland
  - Vanni, Lippo - Illuminated leaf from a gradual, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 204)
    Art description: Lippo Vanni (Italian, active 1341-1375) Illuminated leaf from a gradual, with historiated initial "I" enclosing a miniature of St. Anthony of Padua, Sienna, circa 1350 On vellum, 21 1/2 x 14 1/2" Purchased from Howell, San Francisco, California
  - Velde, Willem van de - The Prow of a Man of War, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of photographs and a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 205)
    Art description: Willem van de Velde (Dutch, 1611-1693) - The Prow of a Man of War Black chalk and wash, 11 1/2 x 15 1/4" Purchased from Bernard Houthakker, Amsterdam, Netherlands - Seventeenth Century Dutch Ship Pencil and wash, 15 x 19 3/8" Purchased from Nystad, The Hague, Netherlands
  - Velde, Willem van de - Seventeenth Century Dutch Ship, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 6, Folder 206)
    Art description: Willem van de Velde (Dutch, 1611-1693) Seventeenth Century Dutch Ship Pencil and wash, 15 x 19 3/8" Purchased from Nystad, The Hague, Netherlands The photograph that corresponds to the negative in the file can be found in Velde, Willem van de – The Prow of a Man of War, 1966, Box 6, Folder 205.
  - Venetian, Anonymous, 18th Century - An Altarpiece/Head of a Young Man, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 7, Folder 207)
    Art description: Venetian (probably), Anonymous, 18th Century - An Altarpiece (recto) Pen and ink, 14 1/8 x 9" - Head of a Young Man (verso) Pen and ink, 9 x 14 1/8" Purchased from Bernard Houthakker, Amsterdam, Netherlands
  - Vernet, Joseph - Drawings of Italian scenes, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 7, Folder 208)
    Art description: Joseph Vernet (French, 1714-1789) - View of the Temple of Saturn, in the Forum, Rome, 1740-1745 Pen and pencil, with bistre wash and Chinese ink, 20 x 13 7/8" - View of Capo Miseno seen between Cumae and Pozzuoli, facing the Island of Procida, 1740-1745 Pen and pencil, with bistre wash and Chinese ink, 13 5/8 x 19 5/8" - View of Churches on the Caelian Hill in Rome, seen from the Aventine, 1740-1745 Pen and pencil, with bistre wash and Chinese ink, 11 13/16 x 17 5/16" - View of the Ruins of the Temple of Diana at Pozzuoli, 1740-1745 Pen and pencil, with bistre wash and Chinese ink, 12 5/8 x 20" Purchased from M. Knoedler, New York, New York
  - Vickers, Alfred Gomersal - Church of the Bonds of St. Peter, Moscow, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 209)
    Art description: Alfred Gomersal Vickers (English, 1810-1837) Church of the Bonds of St. Peter, Moscow Pencil, 6 x 8 1/2" Purchased from Durlacher Bros., New York, New York
  - Vickers, Alfred Gomersal - The Moskoi Gate, Kremlin, Moscow, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 210)
    Art description: Alfred Gomersal Vickers (English, 1810-1837) The Moskoi Gate, Kremlin, Moscow Pencil, 7 1/4 x 5" Purchased from Durlacher Bros., New York, New York
  - Vickers, Alfred Gomersal - Street Scene, Moscow, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 211)
    Art description: Alfred Gomersal Vickers (English, 1810-1837) Street Scene, Moscow Pencil, 6 x 8 3/4" (Sight) Purchased from Durlacher Bros., New York, New York
  - Vickers, Alfred Gomersal - View of Potsdam, 1966-2019; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 212)
    Art description: Alfred Gomersal Vickers (English, 1810-1837) View of Potsdam Pencil, 10 1/2 x 16" Purchased from Durlacher Bros., New York, New York
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted - Open in 2029
  - Villon, Jacques - Composition, 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 213)
    Art description: Jacques Villon (French, 1875-1963) Composition, 1959 Color lithograph, 9 x 13" Purchased from Berggruen, Paris, France The photograph that corresponds to the negative in the file is in Villon, Jacques - Orly, 1966, Box 7, Folder 214
  - Villon, Jacques - Orly, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of photographs and a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 214)
    Art description: Jacques Villon (French, 1875-1963) - Composition, 1959 Color lithograph, 9 x 13" - Orly, 1962 Color lithograph, 11 1/8 x 18 1/4" Purchased from Berggruen, Paris, France
  - Visentini, Antonio - Ink and wash drawings of classical and contemporary buildings, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a set of photographs and a corresponding set of photograph negatives. (Box 7, Folder 215)
    Art description: Antonio Visentini (Italian, 1688-1782) - 1. Tempio della des Vestale in Roma, circa 1730-1770 Ink and wash, 15 x 20" - 2. Tempio della Sibbila Atiuoli, circa 1730-1770 Ink and wash, 15 x 20" - 3. Faciata della Capela di S. Pietro Momtorio, circa 1730-1770 Ink and wash, 20 x 15" - 4. Faciata della Prospetivo nel Palazo Spada in Roma, circa 1730-1770 Ink and wash, 20 x 15" - 5. Tempio dantonino e Faustina in Roma, circa 1730-1770 Ink and wash, 15 x 20" - 6. Tempio di Nimes in Francia, circa 1730-1770 Ink and wash, 15 x 20" Purchased from B. Weinreb, London, United Kingdom
  - Vliet, Henrik van - Interior of the Old Church in Delft, 1967; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 216)
    Art description: Hendrik van Vliet (Dutch, 1611-1675) Interior of the Old Church in Delft Oil on panel, 15 3/8 x 13" Purchased from H.L. Shickman, New York, New York
  - Volpato, Giovanni and Giovanni Ottaviani - Raphael's Loggias in the Vatican, Rome, 1967; File contains still images. Images are photograph negatives. (Box 7, Folder 217-218)
    Art description: Giovanni Volpato (Italian, 1733-1803) and Giovanni Ottaviani (Italian, 1735-1808) (after Savorelli and Camporesi) Raphael's Loggias in the Vatican, Rome 1772-1777 Hand-colored engravings Purchased from B. Weinreb, London, United Kingdom The photographs that correspond to the negatives in the file can be found in Miscellaneous artwork, 1967-1968, Box 7, Folder 224-225
  - Ward, James - Burnt Rock, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 219)
    Art description: James Ward (English, 1769-1859) Burnt Rock Watercolor and pencil, 9 x 14 1/2" (Sight) Purchased from Thos. Agnew and Sons, London, United Kingdom
  - Whistler, James Abbott McNeill - Thames Police, 1966; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 220)
    Art description: James Abbott McNeill Whistler (American, 1834-1903) Thames Police, 1859 Etching, 6 x 9" Purchased from Ernest Brown and Philipps, London, United Kingdom
  - Wilkie, Sir David - A Study for the "Village Politicians", 1966; File contains a still image. Image is a photograph negative. There is also an image on photo stock paper. (Box 7, Folder 221)
    Art description: Sir David Wilkie (Scottish, 1785-1841) A Study for the "Village Politicians" Watercolor, 11 x 14 1/4" Purchased from Spink and Son, Ltd., London, United Kingdom
  - Goddard, George Henry - Birdseye View of San Francisco and Surrounding Country, undated (Box 7, Folder 222)
  - Yoshiharu - The Great Foreign Elephant, 1967; File contains still images. Images consist of a photograph and a photograph negative. (Box 7, Folder 223)
    Art description: Yoshiharu (Japanese, 19th Century) The Great Foreign Elephant, circa 1865 Woodblock, 14 5/8 x 29 1/2" (Sight) Purchased from R.E. Lewis, San Francisco, California
  - Miscellaneous artwork, 1967-1968; File contains still images. Images consist of photographs and photograph negatives. (Box 7, Folder 224-225)